Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Charles Friend papers, 1982-1988 and undated RL.11594
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Charles Friend papers
1982-1988 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11594
1.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. Charles Friend was an executive in the JWT London Office and Area Director with JWT's European Division. Collection consists of correspondence, periodical reports and other printed materials documenting the management of various JWT offices in Europe. The bulk of correspondence pertains to JWT offices in Denmark, Portugal and Sweden. Topics of correspondence include coordination of client relations and advertising campaigns, relocation of staff, agency performance. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. Charles Friend was an executive in the JWT London Office and Area Director with JWT's European Division. Friend came to JWT from Norman Craig & Kummel where he was an international management specialist. At JWT, Friend served as Managing Director and President of JWT Peru before transferring to the London Office as Area Director with JWT Europe.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Charles Friend papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Harry Clark papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Offices
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. David Baker papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Michael Cooper-Evans papers
Collection Overview
Collection consists of correspondence, periodical reports and other printed materials documenting the management of various JWT offices in Europe. The bulk of correspondence pertains to JWT offices in Denmark, Portugal and Sweden. Topics of correspondence include coordination of client relations and advertising campaigns, relocation of staff, agency performance. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Europe; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Denmark; Advertising agencies -- Portugal; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Charles Friend Papers, 1982-1988 and undated.; 1
  - Agency Performance Evaluations--Guidelines and Format, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Denmark, 1986-1987; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - European Division booklet notes, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - European offices client lists, 1984 (Box 1)
  - European office top ten client lists, 1988 (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 1988 (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 1988 (Box 2)
  - JWT Italia account review, 1984 (Box 2)
  - JWT Vienna--Creditanstalt (bank) presentation, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Portugal, 1988; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Procedures and Organisation for European Strategy Planning, undated (Box 2)
  - Spain, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Sweden, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Sweden, 1987-1988; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Sweden--3 Year Plan, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Switzerland, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Turkey, 1988 (Box 3)